ZIQIANG XU

Front-End Developer

SUMMARY

Two years of formal education in a Computer Science related field. One year of studying and practicing frontend technologies. Have built over 10 projects independently using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React. Debug and add new features to existing projects on a regular basis. Fluent in writing React components and very familiar with how React works. Team player with good communication skills. Have worked in agile environments before.

CONTACT

tiomsity@gmail.com

3129758334

Chicago, IL

linkedin.com/in/ziqiangxu in

github.com/TIMZZZ19 (7)

<u>ziqiang-xu-portfolio.netlify.app/</u> (Please visit to view more projects)

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript React, Bootstrap, Tailwind Git & GitHub

EDUCATION

Master's

Data Science Illinois Institute of Technology Aug 2019 - Dec 2021 Chicago, IL

PROJECTS

FoodApp2

food-order-react-app2.netlify.app/

- A fictional online food-ordering App built with React;
- Used Context API for managing global states;
- Used Firebase real-time database to store order data;
- Practiced all the basics in React, including components, props, state, hooks, portals, CSS module.

Pig Game

pig-game-with-timer-mode.netlify.app/

- The classic simple dice game brought to life with React;
- Developed an easy-to-use UI for user to control the game progress, select game modes, choose target score and time limit;
- Designed and developed the timer mode, in which players can complete against each other during the time limit they set;
- Developed a highly cohesive and loosely coupled software system.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Science Practicum Program

Accenture

Aug 2020 - Dec 2020 / Chicago, IL

- Worked in a data science team of 4 persons in an agile environment;
- Programmed in Python for preprocessing and visualizing data;
- Carried the entire team in the last sprint where I actively reached out to geneticist John Blischak at the University of Chicago, under his help and my own persevering research, I accomplished the challenge all by myself.

Engineering Intern

Warren County Engineer's Office

Jan 2017 - Aug 2017 / Cincinnati, OH

- Assisted senior engineers in two local roadway redesign projects;
- Worked with a co-worker to conduct outdoor engineering surveying and finished inspection for around 400 culverts over a summer.